name is Nicola and I'm an Al developer
and one of the areas that I'm working on
is the cloud migration the next area
that I'm also working on is the upgrade
so I'll will be covering these parts
today today with me I have
Roman uh yes hello my name is Roman
saber I'm the engineering manager of the
control plane team we are part of the
business Central platform and are
responsible for the services that manage
business Central environments in the
cloud for administration and among many
other things also for cloud migration
and that's why we're here
today yeah hello my name is Julia and
I'm a developer in business Central and
before I was a developer in N Vision so
worked in many areas and today I
responsible for cloud
migration replication engine yeah all
right thank
you so we have prepared a lot of content
in front of you we are going to start
with the journey overview so I'm going
to describe to you how does the cloud
migration Journey looks end to end so
you get an overview of all of the
components that are in play then I'm
going to show you all the steps that you
need to do to prepare for the cloud
migration Journey so all the things that
you should do before you start
replicating data into
cells then Roman is going to do the demo
how you can set up the cloud migration
and he's also going to go deep into the
technical details and Julia is going to
describe to you how is the tool actually
moving the data to the SAS database
during this part they're also going to
cover most commonly occurring errors
they're also going to show you how you
can fix them so you get a more smoother
Cloud migration Journal we are going to
end with upgrade so I'm going to demon
to you the improvements that we did to
the cloud migration from previous
versions so we have implemented some
nice functionality there and we have
also improved the on Prem upgrade so we
have few changes that I believe that you
would really like at the end we will not
have time to go into details for the API
so I will just briefly mention it at the
end so if we are to start the cloud
migration Journey the first stop would
be actually the version
14 and this is a rather important
version because this is the last version
which is supporting
CR as you probably
remember in version 50 we have stopped
the support for C so we could develop a
in an easier way and to give you a nice
features that we have implemented over
time when we have discontinued the 14
The Promise was that you need to upgrade
to the other side because the grass is
greener on the other end with version 15
and if you have been here three years
ago on the BC Tech days in
2019 you may remember this slide so this
was the story back then today the
journey is looking like this and as you
can see we have been busy we have
released seven new six new releases and
we have added a lot of functionality so
you can see that each release is bigger
than the previous release the good news
as well is that the grass is still green
and let's take a look how does the
upgrade Journey look
like the first step is to upgrade to 14
if you're coming from the previous
version then you can do a single step
upgrad to the version 21 skipping all of
the versions in between and if this is
what a customer wants you can go live on
21 or you can replicate the data to SAS
and go live in SAS version this part is
bringing benefits because you're able to
get more control in the on Prem upgrate
and replication is usually a safer step
safer last step than running the upgrate
right but the problem with this part is
that you need to write the upgrade
scripts and to do the on Prem
upate alternative part is that you can
go to 14 and then you can replicate the
data to Sauce you can go straight to the
latest version of the cloud and then we
will run the upgrate in the sauce
version this part is better because you
don't need to do the on-prem upgrade and
the second benefit that you're getting
is that the upgrade and Cloud
replication is going to be a bit more
forgiving when it comes to Breaking
changes and I will cover it a little bit
later
now before we go forward this picture is
showing one important thing which is
also one of the questions that we are
often getting from you and that question
is for how long are we going to support
the one step upgrade path from 14 and
direct Cloud migration from 14 and as
you can see it's a very important build
for us because it is serving as a bridge
from all of the customers that are on C
to the latest version so the answer to
this one is we are going to support this
part as long as we technically can
because we want to make you as efficient
when you're running the
operat now there are two technical
challenges which are also visible from
the picture as you can see the longer
you wait the longer time it's going to
take to do the upgrade because with each
functionality that we add we are also
unfortunately adding time to operate we
are aware of this problem and we did few
improvements in this release to address
this problem to make the up actually
take short of
time the second problem is that the
software on the previous versions before
14 is getting out of support and in
today's world it's presenting a huge
security risk to run your business on a
software that is not officially
supported anymore and this is actually
one of the main drivers for the cloud
migration that we have also heard from
you guys is that the customer wants to
go into SAS so they do not need to buy
the new licenses for SQL Server windows
and other products so this is one of the
reasons to prioritize the cloud
migration to
s for a few interesting statistical
details in the last 30 days we had 564
unique customers migrating and we can
see that this number in the last few
months was between 500 and
600 and as you can see the versions 20
and versions 14 are the most popular
ones so approximately one one third of
the customers is coming from the version
14 and we are of course supporting all
of the versions between the version 14
all the way up to the version
20 and we planed to do this as long as
we
can now this was the overview so I hope
that you have understood which steps do
we need to take and now we are going to
go into
specifics and we are going to start with
step number one and that's upgrading to
14 oops
ah it works this di so as part of the
upgrading to 14 there are two things
that you should do first one is to align
the table definitions and to clean up
the
date aligning the table definitions this
could sound like a big task but in
reality it's relatively simple because
out of all of the properties that we
could have on the table objects these
properties are must for both Cloud
migration and for operate so you must
align primary keys both in the source
and the target database and you need to
align the field names and data types if
you don't do this the cloud migration
and upgrate is going to
fail now following things Cloud
migration is able to handle but if
you're running the on Prem upgrade
you're going to be affected so if you
have different names if you need to
prefix you the table name with the
three-letter prefix or suffix you can
use table mapping and Roman in will show
how you can do
that now this is a biggest problem that
we have heard from you because almost
all of the customers have added
additional fields to Microsoft on
tables and if you have not refactored
them in a good way the cloud migration
is going to ignore these fields
currently so we will replicate the Full
Table ignoring the fields that you have
added to the main
table if you're running upgrate upgrade
is going to fail now the good news is
that we understand understand it's a big
problem and we have a prototype that we
are currently testing so we believe that
during the cloud migration we will be
able to split the main table with table
extensions into main table and table
extension without the need for you to
write any code and if we are successful
we are going to announce it so just keep
your eyes open there might be an
announcement coming in a few
weeks and as the last things is the
table IDs and secondary keys Cloud
migration does not care about these at
all they are only important for the on
Prem upate so if you are Cloud migrating
from 14 on an earlier version you can
also change and renumber the
objects for cleaning up the data we are
basically unlimited when it comes to the
size of the data that you can Cloud
migrate but it's a good idea to clean up
the data before you trigger the cloud
migration and if you're going to do
something our ask is to clean up up the
corrupted code Fields so the corrupted
code fields are usually coming from the
times before we had a SQL datab base so
customers were able to enter new align
characters lowercase characters and
other non-printing characters to the
code Fields SQL doesn't like it and this
field if you copy it you will not be
able to see that it has a new align
character you need to detect it with a
dedicated SQL
query issue is that if you Cloud migrate
with these fields any any code
modifications read delete operation is
going to fail and we are often seeing
issues with the loop like this one so if
you do customer findet and then you Loop
and modify the customers when we reach
one of these two customers it is going
to fail with the AR record does not
exist because platform is unable to read
the records with new line
characters to fix it we have in invoke
nav sanitized field action and my
recommendation is that you take the copy
of the customer database run it once to
identify which tables have the problem
and then you can sanitize their
production database even before you
start doing the Cloud migration you can
optimize them when you know which tables
have the problem with Dash table ID
parameter and customers are going to be
happy because they're most likely
experiencing issues with these records
on
front uh company names could have the
same problem they're not going to be
covered by by the poell commandlet
because it's not a code it's a text
field but the problem is basically the
same you can use a query like this to
detect if the company name has a
problem and the issue is that the cloud
migration is not going to pick it up and
you need to rename the companies before
the cloud
migration now for cleaning up the data
uh you should know all of these reports
but I would recommend that you go to the
data archive page because it is listing
all of the reports that you can use to
compress the entries or to delete the
records that are off to date and it's a
good idea to do it before the cloud
migration all right and with that I'm
going to hand it over to Roman for the
second
part thanks
um all right let's have a
look let's have a look at the cloud
migration under the hood so on the left
hand side
here we have our source environment a
business Central on Prem installation
with a SQL Server database on the right
hand side we have our destination a
business Central online
environment with a an Azure SQL
database so we're using Azure data
Factory for cloud migration and Azure
data Factory is a cloud-based data
integration service that allows to copy
move transform form data across various
data
sources one of
the uh main concepts of azure data
Factory are pipelines and these
pipelines are essentially groupings of
activities and these activities copy
move transform uh the data or also
orchestrate the flow of
data the third piece here is the
integration runtime this is the compute
infrastructure that Azure data Factory
is using and especially for a case like
here where we have our source in a
private Network in an on-prem
installation on on the customer site it
is a self-hosted integration runtime and
this is installed within the network of
the customer on Prem and then registered
with our Azure data f
ctory and in that way it allows us to do
secure copy of the data from from on
pram into the cloud where we then uh
take it further with an Azure
integration runtime to copy the data
into the destination SQL
database um important to know here that
there is no NST needed no NST running
needed um we really connect directly to
the database and the self-hosted
integration runtime is also doing only
calls to the outside to the Azure data
Factory that is been linked
with if your Source database is in Azure
already then we can use an Azure
integration
runtime and then the data goes into the
cloud and from there we follow the same
flow copied into our destination
database so the first step to make this
work is to do the setup so if you go in
in your destination environment to the
cloud
migration wizard the setup wizard you
need to provide the information about
the SQL
Server what are the the connection
string and what is your integration
runtime that you want to
use we have several Azure data factories
running and we use load balancing to
find the best one for for a particular
um um Cloud migration run and um in the
first step we register the your uh
integration runtime we exchange the
authentication key and then these two
are
linked once that is done we create a
preparation
Pipeline and this preparation pipeline
does a couple of checks so checks the
destination
and the source for example looking at
the compatibility level looking at the
version to the versions match and if the
checks succeed then we continue and
create a bunch of stored procedures
again on both sides on the source and on
the
destination we also read the list of
companies from from the source and look
at the list of extensions that are
installed on the destination and then
based on this
information prepare a list of
tables that need to be copied and also
how to copy
them with this information then we
create a replication Pipeline and this
is then the actual pipeline that is
going to do the copy this pipeline is
going to sit there basically knowing
about all the tables the extensions what
needs to be done and is is ready to run
once you actually trigger the
application so once all of these steps
have have been done we Mark the
environment as ready for migration and
we clean up the preparation
pipeline so we're actually quite excited
to see many Cloud migrations running
over the last month and also years and
um we we're continuously looking into
improving the flow improving the
experience and uh as part of that we we
are regularly looking at what are the
most common errors and failure cases so
I want to give a bit of um advice maybe
some some tips uh to to avoid these
these common pitfalls that that we
see um so one of the things uh you can
imagine is that the user requires
certain permissions um um if those
permissions are missing we have uh error
messages like like these ones here and
um
and it it basically points to a couple
of things so one is that the user that
is doing the setup in BC has to have the
super
role if it's a delegated admin then
there needs to be the customer consent
given to run
successfully the SQL user itself also
needs a couple of things uh so on server
level uh the CIS admin role and for the
for the DB uh DB owner role that allows
us to to do all the uh preparations and
Creations of St
procedures so user permissions um we
also see uh frequently um errors in the
connection string
um for example um keywords that don't
match or parameters missing and uh I
just pasted here a a an example link so
it it has to be exactly like this um the
connection string we have it also
documented in the documentation and if
it's a Azure SQL database you can find
your connection string on the Azure
portal go to the resource and you can
you can copy it from
there um we also see SQL timeouts um
which then look like an activity timing
out in the aure data Factory um and
mitigation for that is so there there
are certain minimum requirements for the
selfhosted integration runtime um one of
them is also uh minimum uh net
4.72 um and we have seen a couple of um
database query performance optimizations
that
help um in in those steps so uh one of
them is to update the statistics the
query uh performance statistics which
you can do uh by running St procedure
and uh also the indexes um so by
reorganizing the indexes we have seen um
also performance improvements and um
avoiding uh timeout situations so this
is a couple of of of
tips um also we we we post this on the
on the documentation um have a look
there uh we also see cases where the
product type or the version is not
matching and and
um this shows up as a more generic um
error messages error message um
so pick pick the the current version if
the major version so it's important that
the major version is is matching here
from from your source and the
destination um otherwise uh pick
previous version and one thing maybe
that is also easily missed is there's
this um property in the attendant
database property table uh the
application version that needs to be
updated manually after an upgrade on
Prem um so if that one is missed and
doesn't match then we also see see this
error okay um finally also we see SQL
failures to connect
um um this is um typically um showing up
uh like this so we have SQL fail to
connect um
or um some firewall issues
and
and we we recommend to do some some some
essential connection checks uh before um
so verify that the user can connect to
the on Prem DB user uh correct uh check
also that the machine that is running
the integration runtime has the ability
to access the SQL
Server um you can run a simple
query here um using the
um basically remote execution and check
the connection there on the firewall
level um make sure that the client IP
address has is is is WID listed um and
has access so this can be done with this
St procedure and finally also um the um
SQL Server that's um running needs to
allow remote access
which you can do with with this St
procedure so once the checks are
successful and we have created this
replication pipeline we can actually do
the migration and the replication and
with this I'm going to hand over to Yia
thank you
Roman
right so uh you go uh to start the
replication run you go to Cloud
migration management page and there is
an action
there so run migration now and that
would start a new migration run so what
does it do it makes a call to the Asia
data Factory to your replication
pipeline that is stored during the setup
and this replication pipeline starts
executing and it instructs the
self-hosted integration runtime to pick
the data from the on premise database
and copy it into an Asia blob storage we
use that as a temporary store for the
data and it's regional so your data is
not moving outside of your region um and
then the integration runtime in Asia
would uh take the data from The Blob
storage and move it to the tenant
database in the cloud we do it in two
steps for for a couple of reasons so one
is the performance the most um uh slow
Pro process is the transfer of the data
from the on premus database to the cloud
and self-hosted integration runtime has
the ability to compress the data so this
step is actually running faster of
course then we have to decompress when
we are in the cloud already but it's
faster because we are in Asia so this
this is how it runs and if you have
large tables that have to be replicated
then these tables are going through
through exactly this path so they
copying one by one uh through the Asia
blob storage and you can watch the
progress on the cloud migration
management page if you refresh the
status each large table that has been
replicated would show in the statistics
there
immediately but for the smaller tables
we introduced uh an
optimization so we actually collect the
data from all the smaller tables we
serialize them into huge Json then we
compress it and then we chunk it into
the records of a special table and then
just this one table is being replicated
going the same path and on in the Asia
side the store procedures that are
running in the tenant database they
would get this records again combine a
huge uh Json de compress it and then put
the records one by one one into the
corresponding tables in the tenant
database so if you watch for the status
this process is moving a lot of tables
but you won't see the progress
immediately so you have to wait because
we report it by the end when the records
are actually in the ten
database uh so when you do the
replication the first time we replicate
all tables we call it a full replication
uh run and then we actually use uh SQL
change tracking
versions uh to make this subsequent runs
faster so if you run replication again
we won't move all the data but only
those that are Delta change so
incremental uh that would make it
faster we are using change tracking so
it's important that you do not replace
or you don't change your on premise
database otherwise the change tracking
becomes invalid we have to drop it and
we have to do the full replication again
again and if this happens you'll see a
longer replication run again so that was
um for the process and now uh so the
replication is done by Asia data Factory
and it's mostly very stable we don't see
so many errors as in setup you see that
it's completely different scale but uh
like three major errors something
happened in the premus during the
replication run or you hit one of the uh
limitations in Asia data Factory itself
it could be either large metadata or
large data so let's see for the premus
intervention you can have uh integration
run time is
offline or you can have invalid object
name and could not find stored procedure
on the SQL level so for the first one uh
our recommendation is uh you keep the
machine that hosts your integration run
time online all the time while you're
doing Cloud migration so sometimes
people shut it down to interrupt to
cancel a a replication run that could be
done no problem but if you keep it
offline too long then we actually have
some automated clean procedures that
might just wipe out the whole uh you
know all the Asia resources that you
Associated as your replication and then
you cannot resume it easily you have to
go through the setup again
and for
the um SQL errors this is happening when
you actually replaced the database maybe
you restored it from the backup but you
did it before the replication run
completed so it couldn't continue didn't
find the
object now these are the most difficult
errors that you face they're not very
common there are like maybe 10 errors
per months that we see large metadata
and um so what is metadata data metadata
is a Json serialized description of all
fields in all tables in all extensions
and for all companies that you are
replicating in this particular run and
Asia data Factory has a limitation for
this text description to be less than
four megabytes so it's not very much so
if you try to migrate to many companies
you might get an error message and the
error message is coming directly from
Asia data Factory so it's maybe not uh
easily understandable so one could be
the lookup activity result exceeded the
limitation or the user payload is too
too
large we it's during the runtime of data
Factory and you see them directly we
don't have a chance to to intercept them
and change the uh the Waring there so
yeah if you see that you're uh you're
trying to probably trying to migrate too
many companies at once so we suggest
that you kind of uh reduce the number of
companies for migration you can do it on
cloud migration management page there is
an action there uh to select the
companies so select few companies R the
migration then select the next bdge that
would be much more stable and probably
faster at the end than trying to migrate
a lot of companies at
once um right sometimes you have uh a
lot of extensions installed in your
tenant already in the cloud but you
don't have data for these extensions in
your own premise database so um it's not
harmful as such but why to do that it's
also contributes to the large
metadata thing so we recommend that you
uninstall unnecessary extensions from
the cloud prior to Cloud migration and
then install them back as you start
working with them right and finally you
can for your own extensions you can
exclude some of the tables from cloud
Migration by changing the attribute on
the table on the L table replicate data
to
false then the next uh kind of um type
of Errors is when you're trying to
migrate large data and that could happen
if you if you um you can get it in in
two different parts so when there is a
bulk copy many small tables go in as one
bulk right in this case what we see most
often uh out of memory exception this
out of memory in the Asia data Factory
infrastructure it's not the business
Central infrastructure so we don't have
any control on that but um yeah or task
failed out of memory so what we say um
what we see is that usually it happens
when tenant media table is going through
the bulk and it contains some large
images so it's like a it's a very big
value in a single field that does it
this images are they're not compressible
so um if you see out of memory exception
like that so we recommend you uh a work
around a hack so you can find a St
procedure that was installed in your on
premise database it's called is full
copy uh store procedure and add a block
like that that would redirect tenant
media to be copied one to one to the
cloud and hopefully you will avoid out
of memory
exception if you still get it then just
create a support ticket and we will try
to help you out another large data could
happen when it's table to table full
copy but the error message would be
different so you see this specified row
delimit is incorrect this is happening
when the aure data Factory cannot read
uh The Blob storage the temporary blob
storage so the workaround is the
opposite try to see which table failed
because it's one one to one so you will
see the name the name of the table and
try to redirect it into the bulk so
hopefully it is compressible so it will
it might succeed we reported both of
these errors to a data Factory so maybe
at some point they'll prioritize the
fixes and we won't see it anymore but
today this is what we face right so the
next okay some performance tips
something of that we already talked
about so for your on premise
infrastructure the most important is the
machine with the integration runtime
they have specified their own system
requirements that we have to
honor then if your source is Asia SQL
then you you can monitor the CPU and
memory utilization on in the Asia portal
and you should upscale your database if
you see high consumption during the
cloud migration process then what Roman
already mentioned we have update
statistic and reorganized indexes for
the source database we recommend to do
that before you set up your database for
cloud migration just
once and then uh use a dedicated SQL
Server so don't use this server that is
already busy with some other production
you know activities but uh have have a
server that is only doing cloud cloud
migration then it would be faster yeah
and yeah Universal reduce the number of
companies set up for cloud migration so
what we see is an optimal size is about
10 15 companies it could be more it
depends on your data and depends on the
how many objects you have how many
extensions um yeah but try and see uh
what works for you and one topic that I
wanted to talk more so when you
replicate data we do some default
mapping so you normally you don't think
about it but if you have tables with the
same names both in the on premise and in
the cloud then we just copy them but we
copy them because the SQL names match so
we look at the SQL names and that
usually the company name the table name
and the extension ID so if there is a
full match the data is copied apart
apart from the extra Fields as Nicol
just mentioned so if you edit some
fields that are uh in the on premise but
they're not in the cloud we will just
silently ignore them the nothing happens
no errors no warnings but they're just
not there so another case if you have a
table in the cloud but there is no
marching table in the on premus database
in this case we replicate the data for
all the other tables but for this table
you will see see a warning a warning
like this that the the table doesn't
exist in the local installation so uh in
most cases it's uh safe to ignore it but
uh just make sure that this is expected
that this is what you wanted and you
didn't miss this table just for some
reason right and if you have different
tables for example if you have installed
absortion uh extension and you were
forced to use three letters prefix but
you have data for it in the premise it's
just the table name is different you
still can migrate so uh in the cloud
migration management table we have an
action uh called table mapping and there
if
you uh use it you will be there is a
drop down to choose the extension and
the table and you just type the table
name in indone premise that should be
matching table and we respect this
mappings during the next migration run
we will take the data and move it to to
a table with a different name uh yeah
move all the fields that are compatible
and that have the same names in both
tables so that was uh it for the
replication process and now Nicola is
going to talk What's happen next next
after you replicated data all right
thanks
so for the last step it's going to be
the data upgrade and I'm going to show
to you two improvements that we did to
the existing process the first
Improvement is that we are leveraging
the upgrade Logic for the up if your
Cloud migrating from previous versions
to explain this one in a little bit more
details for version 20 when we have
written the upgrade code that is
specific for version 20 we needed to
take the changes and to adapt them so we
can use them for the cloud migration and
the reason why we need to do this is
because we are unable to invoke the
upgrade Cod units and as you know the
change is needed because you cannot
access obsolete removed fields from non
upgrade scope now some of the partners
that have also written the upgrade code
that would like to use it would
essentially need to do the same change
take it and adopt it so it serves the
cloud migration and then the problem is
when the upgrade 21 comes we need to do
the same operations both you and us so
and essentially we should not be doing
this because we should be able to reuse
the upgrate code that we have written
and we should be able to remove this
extra code and extra Op loged with it so
this is the first Improvement because we
are triggering the full upgrade code all
apps are going to be included and you
will have a single upgrate Logic the
next benefit is that we are going to
move the tenant to the status of
upgrading which means that hot fixes are
not going to interrupt the upgrade also
it is going to be a single session which
means you will get a more stable upgrade
also you're going to get all of the
reporting and cemetry that we have
automatically in included and in case
the upgrade fails you'll get an
automatic bit
restore to show you the flow in action
so if you go to the cloud migration page
and invoke Run update now we are going
to warn you that you're going to lose
the access to the environment because
upgrade will start and that you can
track the status in the admin Center so
if you say yes you will get the message
that the upgrade was scheduled and now
you can go to the admin Center and you
will see that the status has been
flipped to updating if you go to the
operations tab you will see that we are
loging the history and you will see that
the upgrade operation is running if you
try to access the environment you'll get
sorry you cannot access it we are
running upgrades
and the main benefit of this one is as I
said no hot fixes will be running and
upgrade needs to be this only session
that is running on the server because if
you're using the system you may
incidentally cause locks and cause
errors during the operate
process now if you go back to the admin
Center and you refresh approximately
after 3 minutes the status will flip to
active and then if you go back to the
business
Central you're going to to so okay and
back to the cloud migration
page the status is going to be flipped
to completed you will see it in a second
and now you're able to go live after
this
step now in case the upgrade fails then
in this state you can go back to the
operations Tab and you'll see that the
operation has failed you'll get a full
stack Trace we are looking into
providing you with a nice error message
message as well so you can see why did
it fail and you can go back to the
business Central you'll see that the
tenant is operational because we have
restored it as point in time and here
you will see that upgrade is fending
because it was restored to before we ran
the upgrade so now you can fix the
errors replicate additional data or try
to run the upgrade again so with this
new flow you're also getting an
automatic poting time
store the good news as well is that
because we are just rolling this one out
we are still supporting the old upgrade
flow so if you took any dependencies to
how the system used to work in the past
it is still possible to trigger the old
engine we just we can programmatically
enable the old upgrade part if your
solution is affected by
this then for the last topic we did some
faster upgrades and faster and upgrade
are usually not the words that you can
hear together together right usually it
is much slower so for this one we got
the data transfer feature and
unfortunately I will not be able to talk
about it much I will just briefly cover
it the problem is that most of our long
running upgrade is actually being caused
because we are moving obsolete removed
Fields onto the new fields and we are
doing it in an in efficient way by using
the loopy loopy solution where you are
looping over the entries and modifying
them
the problem with this one is that it is
rather slow so if you want to update 1
million entries it's going to take
anywhere between 2 hours or 24 hours and
more the reason why is it fluctuating so
much is because it depends on how strong
is the SQL Server how many table
extensions you have and how many
subscribers you have to the on modify l
so it can be 2 24 hours or even
more now with with data transfer
features we have a much more efficient
way of doing this so instead of doing
the air Loop you would say which table
is being mapped to which table you can
add Source filters you can add join
statements you can map Fields one to
another and when you call Copy fields we
are actually going to invoke a SQL query
and we are not going to raise any events
so it is going to be very fast to give
you the comparison number numbers with
data transfer one to million entries is
approximately taking two to 5 minutes so
with this feature now we are able to
update the large tables like customer
legendaries yep now it has some
limitations because it's a very powerful
feature we can only use it in upgrade
scope to initialize the new Fields so
the only usage we can use it for is to
move the obsolete removed Fields onto
the new field because otherwise it would
be be a breaking change if we do not
raise the
events and since it is a powerful
feature currently it's marked as Target
on Prem which means that you will
unfortunately not be able to use it for
SAS solution but you can use it for your
own unpre upgrade if you want to make it
faster now with every new release we are
getting questions how many long running
methods have introduced and I'm happy to
say that for this release we have
shrinked the number of long running
methods by 11 because we use this new
data transfer feature to optimize the
long running upgrad that we historically
know that it has
existed so hopefully the journey to the
cloud is going to look like this it
should take much less time to operate
the
on-prem and because we are reusing the
same engine it should take much less
time to also migrate to SAU since we are
reusing the engine we get all of the
benefits that we usually get
yet and I hope that the ultimate test
basically it's going to be done by you
guys so we are looking forward to your
feedback but we believe that the upgrade
to 21 it's going to be faster than the
upgrade to version 20 so with this I
hope that we have fixed the long running
upgrade
problem and for the end we have the API
from managing the cloud migrations end
to end so this is very useful if you're
doing many Cloud migrations or if you
want to move many companies like 50 or
something like that you can basically
the entire flow that you have seen today
you can automate it through the apis you
can do the setup company management and
then you can manage the cloud Migration
by doing it on the BCT Tech uh GitHub
you have the example of all of the apis
you can try it out and in case of any
issues if you would like to provide us
feedback we recommend that you join us
on the BC class Cloud migration ymer you
can see that we have
870 Partners here partners are also
providing with a lot of interesting
information helping others so please
join us on Yammer and with this we are
ending the presentation we are just out
of time so if you have any questions I
would invite you to come down and ask us
a question and then we can discuss it or
otherwise you can find us around and we
can talk about any topic thank
[Applause]
[Music]
you